行尸走肉
第十一季  第十六集[半季终]
19个小时及一场神迹以前
过来
Come here.
东西都带了吗
You have everything?
小猪带了吗
Piggy Pig?
我已经不是小孩子了  妈妈
I'm not a baby anymore, Mom.
对  我忘了
Right. I forgot.
我不想去
I don't wanna go.
这只是暂时的  好吗
It's only temporary. Okay?
我保证
I promise.
-我想帮忙  -我知道  赫谢尔
- I wanna help. - I know you do, Hershel,
但这次不行
but not this time, okay?
大概有多远
How far do you think?
往南12英里左右
12 miles south, give or take.
如果走得快  天黑前就能到
Should get there before dark if we move fast.
然后我们很快就回来了
Then we'll be back before you know it.
好吗
Okay?
来吧
I got you.
威廉·弥尔顿总统  1982年
猜吧
Call it.
我猜是反面
Tails, I guess.
请去那边
Over there, please.
任务是什么  长官
Gonna give us the assignment, sir?
你们很快就知道了
You'll know soon enough.
《粉碎原子: 宇宙之谜》
-早  -天啊
- Morning. - Oh, my God.
我以为你还在睡
I thought you were still asleep.
我刚睡得很香
Well, I was -- soundly so.
昨晚很愉快  不是吗
I thought we had a lovely night, didn't we?
是的
Yeah, we did.
你在看什么
What are you reading?
只是
Um, just...
物理学方面的书
stuff on physics.
"运动中的物体"之类的
"An object in motion" -- you know.
我只想让你知道
Just so you know...
你是我在平平无奇的人生中
you are the most remarkable human I have ever met
遇到的最了不起的人
in my heretofore uneventful life.
好  别太过了
Okay, let's not get carried away here.
你在各方面都很美
You're beautiful in every way.
谢谢
Thank you.
我要准备去上班了
I have to get ready for work.
如果你对我
If you're having hesitation
让你做的事有所犹豫的话
about what I've asked you to do...
不
No.
我说了我会做
I said I'll do it.
我只是
I just, um...
你可以告诉我
You can tell me.
我只是忍不住想  这样做之后会怎样
I just can't stop thinking about what happens after we do this.
这地方逼人保持现状
This place pushes on people to keep things the same.
我只是担心我们会被逼到崩溃
I just worry they'll keep pushing till we all break.
安全
Clear.
这个房间安全
This room is clear!
他们没有分散
They're not splitting up.
-安全  -迟早会的
- Clear! - Yeah, they will.
-现在也许是最好的机会  -不  太冒险了
- This might be our best shot. - No, it's too risky.
我们得赶紧办完这事回家
We need to just get through this and get back home.
没有什么"办完这事"好吗
There is no "Getting through this," All right?
我们身陷险境  只能杀出去
We are in the shit till we find a way to fight our way out.
我们继续往北走  远离大部队
Look, we keep heading north, away from our group.
找到机会就下手
We find our moment, we take it.
有什么好聊的
Hey, what's with the chit-chat?
我们需要休息
Man, we need a break.
我们一直在忙
Been doing this for a while now.
我们会继续忙下去
And we'll keep doing this for a while,
假如有必要的话
if that's what it takes.
你们查过查尔斯顿吗
Hey, you check Charleston yet?
怎么了  查尔斯顿有什么
Why? What's in Charleston?
屋顶上的人说
There's a rumor up on the rooftops
他们在那里交易武器
they trade for weapons and stuff.
那里可能有线索  也可能没有
Might be something, might not.
让开
Move!
罗马诺  你们在哪
Romano, what's your 20?
距最后一个哨站13英里
13 miles past the last outpost.
第二个地点安全  还剩一个地点
Second location is cleared, one more to go.
收到
Copy that.
出发
Let's move.
霍恩斯比在问我们的情况
Hornsby's checking in on us.
我们要当心了
We need to watch our backs.
对
Yeah.
似乎更接近了
Seems like it's getting closer.
确实
Because it is.
妈妈
Mom?
我没事
I'm okay.
不  你有事
No, you're not.
赫谢尔
Hershel...
我过去做的一切
Everything I've done...
我仍在做的一切
And everything I still do...
都是为了让我们有选择
is so that we have choices.
我们现在去的地方  你可能不喜欢
The place that we're going right now, you may not like it.
但我向你保证
But I promise you,
这是正确的选择
it is the right choice.
就目前来说
For now.
很好
Good.
你们到了  这边
Oh, you made it! This way.
令人激动
Exciting.
你不觉得吗
Don't you think?
一切都圆满了
Things are coming together.
你能得到杀掉你家人的女人的头皮
You get the scalp of the woman who killed your family,
而我终于可以不受干扰地工作了
and I finally get to do my job without interference.
人人都是赢家
Everybody wins.
除了有些人
Well... not everybody.
等她死了
I'll need to see.
我要亲眼看看
When she's dead.
等她死了  我要亲眼看看
I'll need to see her when she's dead.
你会看到的
You will.
走吧
Come on.
好吧  卡住了
Okay, this thing is stuck.
玛姬
Maggie.
小子
Hey, kid.
你确定霍恩斯比和他的人会来吗
And you're sure this guy Hornsby and his men are coming?
是的  伊莱哲昨晚在墙外
Yes, Elijah spotted a few of them 5 miles
五英里的地方看到了他们
outside our walls last night.
你怎么想
Thoughts?
你帮过我们
You helped us,
我很感激
and I am grateful.
我完全不介意照顾那孩子
And I got no problem watching the kid at all.
但我妻子安妮怀孕了
But, Annie, my wife, is pregnant,
所以我不会待在一个
so there is no way I'm gonna sit in some
低语者的虫洞里  看着你去
Whisperer worm hole while you're out --
拯救一个压根不值得拯救的破家
I don't know -- saving some shithole of a home that's not worth saving.
尼根  别这样说
Negan, don't.
他是对的
Actually, he's right.
也许山顶寨是不值得拯救
Maybe Hilltop isn't worth saving.
但那里的人们值得拯救
But those people are.
我挑起的这场
This fight that I'm in, that I started,
与霍恩斯比的战斗
with Hornsby --
只有我才能了结它
it's not gonna end until I end it.
我毫不怀疑你能了结
And I got no doubt you will.
但我也毫不怀疑兰斯那个混蛋
But I also got no doubt that you are firmly
现在一心想杀了你  所以
in the crosshairs of this Lance asshole, so...
我会和你一起去
So I'm coming with you.
不  我去做了结
No. I'll finish it.
-玛姬  我们能帮你  -拜托别插手
- Maggie, we can help fight - No, please.
我需要你们待在这里  照顾赫谢尔
I need you to stay here -- with Hershel,
照顾其他人
with those others.
让他们别靠近山顶寨  直到一切结束
Keep them away from Hilltop and safe until this is over.
你知道他不信任我吧
He doesn't exactly trust me, you know?
但我开始信任你了
But I'm starting to.
你在河湾
You saved him...
救过他
at Riverbend.
不管发生什么
Whatever else happens,
不管发生过什么
and whatever else has happened,
我都不会忘记这点
I will never forget that.
天啊
Wow.
你真是心胸宽广  玛姬·李
You have big balls, Maggie Rhee.
我会帮你
I got you.
我也会保护你儿子
And I got your boy.
安妮
Annie...
等一切结束了  他会等着你回来
He'll be waiting for you when this is done.
我向你保证
I promise you that.
谢谢
Thank you.
该死
Oh, shit.
这是上面那位的神迹吧
If that ain't a sign from the Man Upstairs.
据《出埃及记》记载  法老王拒绝释放
并屠杀奴隶  于是上帝降下蝗灾作为惩罚
你们到第二个地点了吗
You at the second location?
目前正在搜查
Clearing that now.
快点完成
Finish.
然后回来
Then head back.
收到  长官  我们这就回去
Copy that, sir. We'll head back.
最后查一遍  然后回家
One last sweep, then home.
好  很好
All right, great.
我来领头
I'll lead.
掩护左边
Cover left, cover left!
包围他们
Keep 'em surrounded!
从左边包抄  掩护我
Flanking left! Cover me!
我上了  掩护我
Moving up! Cover me, cover me!
当心左边
Watch that left! Watch that left!
霍恩斯比在哪
Where's Hornsby?
去你的
Screw you.
你来选
It's your choice.
可能
Maybe...
可能在10英里外
Maybe 10 miles out.
他说
He said he wanted...
他想清场
Said he wanted to clear the field.
"清场"
"Clear the field"?
只留下盟友
Leave only allies behind.
玛姬
Maggie.
罗马诺  你在吗
Romano, you there?
他已经不在了
He ain't here anymore.
立刻出发
Move! Now!
在世界崩溃之后
And when this world fell,
我们收集了散落的碎片
we gathered up the scattered pieces,
再次将它们拼凑了起来
and we put them back together again.
这并不容易  我们偶尔会却步
It wasn't easy, and we faltered at times.
但我们找到了生存的理由
But we found a reason to live
而墙外的一切
when everything outside these walls...
都已经死了
was dead.
麦克斯
Max?
你还好吗
You okay?
你看起来
You seem...
心不在焉
far away.
不  我很好
No, I'm good.
我的心在这里
I'm right here.
麦克斯  你心情不好可以告诉我
Max, if you're having a bad day, you can tell me.
我懂的  知道吗
I do get it, you know?
总是得很"坚强"  不流露感情
Always having to be "Strong," Never show any emotion.
但如果我们不能对彼此流露感情
But if we can't show that to each other,
那还能对谁流露呢
who can we show it to?
很感谢你  帕梅拉
I appreciate it, Pamela.
你知道的  但是
You know I do. But...
我真没事
I am really okay.
在我忘记之前
Oh, before I forget.
会计部发来了创始人日的预算
Accounting sent over the Founders' Day budget.
有五万美元的结余
There's a $50,000 surplus.
太好了
Well, that's great.
如果你愿意听的话  我有个建议
I was gonna suggest something, if you're open to it?
要不然为贫困家庭
How about starting a scholarship fund
设立一个奖学金吧
for our less-fortunate families?
我拟了一份提案  我们可以...
I've put together a proposal, and we could...
这可以吗
Is that... okay?
当然了  我喜欢你的发散思维
Of course! I love your out-of-the-box thinking.
但结余资金也要用在活动上
But any extra funds go right back into the event.
那是一年中最重要的一天
It's our biggest day of the year.
好
Sure.
我理解
I understand.
你真的该走了
You really should get going.
你五点有晚宴
You've got that 5:00 dinner.
对了  谢谢
Yes, thank you.
我真是离不了你  麦克斯
I don't know what I'd do without you, Max.
你也很快会走吧
You're leaving soon, too, right?
马上就走
Right behind you.
重新安置
很抱歉  我不想吓你
I'm so sorry. I didn't mean to scare you.
不  塞巴斯蒂安  你好
No, Sebastian, hi.
你没吓到我
Uh, no, you didn't.
我能帮你做什么吗
Is there something that I can help you --
是的
Yes, uh, is -- is...
我妈妈在生我的气吗
Uh, is my mom pissed at me?
因为我一直要求见她
You know, 'cause I keep asking for her, and -- and...
-却见不到  -她只是
- nothing, so... - It's just been
今天下午很忙
a hectic afternoon, so --
我必须和她谈谈
I gotta talk to her, so could you just --
请你帮我叫一下她  麦克斯
If you could get her for me, Max...
她去参加工作宴了
She's actually at a work dinner,
但我可以帮你传话
but I can get word to her for you.
"传话"
"Get word to her"?
对
Yeah, yeah, why --
你何不帮我去"传话"呢
Why don't you go "Get word to her" for me.
我可是她的独生子
Her only child.
这真是太荒唐了
That is such bullshit.
我很抱歉  塞巴斯蒂安
I'm really sorry, Sebastian,
但我其实也正准备走
but I was actually on my way out, so...
你永远不停
Oh, you never stop!
总是在工作
Working, working, hey.
你真是...  天啊
You just... Oh, God,
你还要把工作带回家吗
I mean, you even take it home with you?
不  我来
Oh, no, that's -- I -- I got it.
没事  没关系
It's okay. That's fine.
下午喝太多咖啡总是让人毛手毛脚
Always clumsy after one too many afternoon coffees, you know?
对
Yeah, it's, uh...
穷人的毒品
poor man's drug.
咖啡因
Caffeine.
没看到霍恩斯比
No sign of Hornsby.
这混蛋总是让别人替他干脏活
Asshole always has somebody else do his dirty work.
看看能否回收他们的武器
See if we can recover any of their weapons.
跟着他们的足迹回营地
Follow their trail back to their camp,
然后了结这一切
and then we end this.
这就去
On it.
准备好了吗  哥们
You ready, bud?
一如既往
As ever.
走吧
Let's do it.
马可
Marco!
趴下
Get down!
不  马可
No. Marco!
快跑
Go, go.
死了几个
How many?
三个
Three.
莉娅  你在哪
Leah, your 20?
莉娅  这是怎么回事
Leah, what the hell was that?!
我把他们引了出来
I drew 'em out.
我要按自己的方法办
I'm doin' this my way.
你的方法害死了我的人
Your way got my men killed!
附带损失
Collateral damage.
我让其他人在20英里的范围内搜索
I've got others fanned over a 20-mile perimeter.
我们会找到他们的
We'll find them.
你最好能找到
You goddamned better.
他的士兵在这里
His troopers are here.
他一定离得很近
He's gotta be close.
是的
Yeah.
还有行尸
We got walkers, too.
他给它们做了陷阱
He set traps for them.
这不是为它们做的
These aren't for them.
这是什么
What is it?
莉娅
Leah.
我们散开  覆盖更大区域
I think we should split up, cover more ground.
你确定是她吗
You sure it was her?
是的
Yes.
快走吧
Go, please.
我来把莉娅和其他人引开
I'll lead Leah and the others away.
我不会丢下你
I am not gonna leave you.
我不会冒险失去你们俩
I will not risk losing you two.
我们能照顾好自己  玛姬
We can handle ourselves, Maggie, okay?
我们也去引开他们  等大家安全了
We'll draw them away, too, and then, when everyone's safe,
再和其他人见面
we'll just go meet up with the others.
我会找到你们的  去吧
I'll find you. Go.
泰勒·戴维斯在名单上
Tyler Davis is on this list.
在盗窃行动中  罗西塔试图帮助的
And the woman Rosita tried to help out
那个女人也在名单上
during the heist is on here, too.
上面还有两百多人
I counted 200 more.
这些数字是什么意思
What about these numbers?
看起来像密码
They look like... codes?
可能是坐标
Maybe coordinates?
所以你认为这是他们藏人的地点
So you think this is about where they're hiding people.
我们为什么不写这个
Why don't we write about that?
现在还不行
No, not yet.
我需要证据
I need proof.
这么重大  这么爆炸性的事
Something this big, this explosive?
我们需要破解密码
We -- We need a key to crack the code.
在那之前
U-Until we have that,
我会先写塞巴斯蒂安的盗窃行动
I'll write about Sebastian's heist...
勒住帕梅拉的脖子
and hang it around Pamela's neck.
当人们发现她不站在自己这边时
I mean, when everyone finds out that she's not on their side,
他们会质疑关于这里的一切
they're gonna question everything about this place.
然后会出现以前提到的起义
Hence the aforementioned uprising.
不  没关系
No, hey, hey, hey! It's -- It's okay.
我觉得我们需要帮助  所以我叫他来了
I thought we could use help, so I told him to come.
抱歉我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
我在为这件事拉更多盟友
Trying to round up a few more for the cause.
-天啊  -我告诉他
- Geez. - I told him
我们需要更多人手  帮我们发文章
we'd needed more people to get the article out.
我有一整个关系网  愿意在黎明时分动手
And I got a whole network, ready and willing to ride at dawn.
我们真要这样做吗
We're doing this?
动手吧
Let's ride.
我等这一刻很久了
I have waited for this moment for a long time.
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want.
很久以来  我自己也想要这个
I wanted it myself for a long time.
你不会杀我  那对我来说太轻松了
You can't kill me. That would be too easy.
如果你想杀我  你早就下手了
If that was what you wanted, you would've done it already.
你想要我受折磨
You want me to suffer.
感受到你所感受的一切
Feel everything that you felt.
所有的痛苦
All the pain.
因为你在心里觉得  这能减轻你的痛苦
'Cause somewhere inside you, you think that'll take away your pain.
减轻不了的
It won't.
你错了
You're wrong.
不只是你
It's not just you.
等我做完之后
By the time I'm done...
你所爱的人都会死
Everyone you love will be dead.
我猜这样就扯平了
Then I guess that makes us even.
我夺走你的家人
I took your family,
你夺走我的家人
you take mine.
因果报应  自有天意
Nature has a way of taking care of these things.
这不是天意
It's not nature.
或命运
Or fate.
这是我们
It's us.
我杀了你的人  因为这是我想要的
I killed your people because it was what I wanted.
如果这是你想要的  莉娅
If this is what you want, Leah...
那就动手吧
Go ahead.
你想要  那就动手吧
You want it, so do it.
快啊
Go on.
他们在里面
They're in there!
长官  你没事吧
Sir, are you okay?
别管了  去另一边
Let it go! On the other side!
谁来支援我
Who's my backup here?
停火
Hold your fire!
现在我们要接管一切
Now we take it all.
帕梅拉·弥尔顿在欺骗你
弥尔顿之子草菅人命  利用无辜者盗窃
欢迎来到亚历山大
联邦
海边小屋汽车旅馆